# **Oliver Otto**

## Consultant bei SNP Schneider-Neureither & Partner AG

oliver.angelin.otto@gmail.com

# Summary

IT professional with advanced knowledge in the field of SAP Solution Manager 7.1 (CRM WebUI, Abap OO), Android and a strong Java background; experience in conception and implementation of sophisticated client-server mobile solutions; dedicated to state of the art software technologies.

# Experience

#### Consultant at SNP Schneider-Neureither & Partner AG

November 2012 - Heute (2 Jahre 7 Monate)

Business Landscape Managment (SAP Solution Manager, Change Request Managment and Incident Handling)

#### Software Developer at Android and Java EE Expert

Januar 2008 - November 2012 (4 Jahre 11 Monate)

# Lead Android Developer/ Freelance Projektarbeit at SapientNitro

März 2012 - Oktober 2012 (8 Monate)

Enterprise Application Integration Android App Development (Car Rental / Vehicle Sales)

## Software Developer at Delta Systemtechnik Horn GmbH

November 2010 - Oktober 2012 (2 Jahre)

Android Development / Java EE - Development of server and client components for a backup solution

### Research Assistant at University of Mannheim

August 2010 - Oktober 2010 (3 Monate)

location fingerprinting using android for indoor positioning

## Intern at Hager & Werken GmbH & Co. KG

Februar 2010 - August 2010 (7 Monate)

### Student at University of Mannheim

Oktober 1999 - Juli 2010 (10 Jahre 10 Monate)

Degree course: Wirtschaftsinformatik / Business Informatics (Diplom) Specialization: Informatics Marketing Business Informatics Finance (not finished) (you have to choose 3 specializations in the advanced study period at the University of Mannheim)

# Graduate (Diploma) at University of Mannheim

März 2009 - Dezember 2009 (10 Monate)

Title: Development of a tracking system using 802.11 and location fingerprinting Grade: 1,3

## Intern at Intergames Entertainment GmbH

November 2007 - Februar 2008 (4 Monate)

# Languages

Englisch (Verhandlungssicher)

**Deutsch** (Muttersprache oder zweisprachig)

# Skills & Expertise

**SAP CRM WebUI** 

SAP ABAP OO

**SAP ABAP** 

**SAP Solution Manager** 

**Incident Managment** 

**Change Request Managment** 

ITIL-v3-Foundations-Zertifizierung

**Certified Scrum Master** 

**Data Migration** 

**SAP Business Server Pages** 

**SAP CRM** 

**SAP UI5** 

**OpenUI5** 

**SAP HANA** 

R

**SQL** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Web Services** 

**JavaScript** 

**HTML** 

**Android Entwicklung** 

**Android SDK** 

**Spring for Android** 

**OrmLite for Android** 

**Java Enterprise Edition** 

Android

Unternehmensanalyse

**Agile Methodologies** 

**Agile Project Managment** 

**Test Driven Development** 

**Agile** 

**Spring Framework** 

**EDI** 

**Consulting** 

**SAP Netweaver** 

**ABAP** 

Anforderungsanalyse

IOT

**Hana Cloud Platform** 

Java

**Hana Cloud Connector** 

**OData** 

**SAP Gateway** 

Scrum

**Agile Methoden** 

**Datenmigration** 

# Certifications

#### **Professional Scrum Master I**

Scrum.org Januar 2015

# In-Memory Data Management (2014) - Implications on Enterprise Systems

Hasso Plattner Institute Oktober 2014

**Sicherheit im Internet** 

Hasso Plattner Institute Dezember 2014

## edX Professional Certificate for Economics of Cybersecurity

edX März 2015

#### Cryptography I

Coursera März 2015

**Game Theory** 

Coursera Dezember 2014

# **Game Theory II: Advanced Applications**

Coursera Februar 2015

Gamification

Coursera Verified Certificates Lizenz VLS9CFUKV8 März 2015

#### The Data Scientist's Toolbox

Coursera Verified Certificates Lizenz 967LHCVGGX Dezember 2014

**R** Programming

Coursera Verified Certificates Lizenz EGNXGHYTSD Dezember 2014

#### SAP Business Suite 4 SAP HANA in a Nutshell

SAP April 2015

# **Digital Transformation and Its Impact**

SAP März 2015

#### How the Internet of Things and Smart Services Will Change Society

SAP April 2015

#### **ABAP Development for SAP HANA**

SAP Oktober 2014

#### **Introduction to SAP HANA Cloud Platform (Repeat)**

SAP März 2015

#### **Introduction to SAP Fiori UX**

SAP Oktober 2014

## **Get to Know SAP's Innovative Enterprise Solutions**

SAP Oktober 2014

# OGSD 7.0 – An Introduction to Oil & Gas Downstream Logistics

SAP Dezember 2014

# SAP Business Warehouse powered by SAP HANA

SAP Dezember 2014

# **BI Clients and Applications on SAP HANA**

SAP Januar 2015

# Rapid Deployment of SAP Solutions (Update Q1/2015)

SAP März 2015

#### **ER22x Justice**

edX August 2013

# Education

# Universität Mannheim

Diplom, Wirtschaftsinformatik (Business Informatics), 1999 - 2010

Grade: 2,1

#### **Interests**

it-security, cryptography, philosophy, photography, ubiquitous computing, internet of things

# **Oliver Otto**

Consultant bei SNP Schneider-Neureither & Partner AG

oliver.angelin.otto@gmail.com



Contact Oliver on LinkedIn